Trent Miller

A cyber security enthusiast who brings a unique blend of technical expertise and analytical problem-solving skills. With several years of experience across multiple job functions and honed abilities in troubleshooting and resolving complex issues all while having a security first mentality. Spreading awareness in the safety and security of each tool, function, and organization is top priority.



Contact

Work History

Address

Madison, WI 53719

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/trent-m-188b6a11a/

WWW

https://azureadtrent.github.io



Technical Profile

- JIRA
- Wireshark
- Linux
- Network Security
- Docker
- Microsoft Windows
- macOS
- Python
- LAN
- Cloud Management
- Palo
- Bash
- Cloud Services
- Splunk



Competencies

Linux Systems

Powershell

Wireshark

Bash

Data security

IT Infrastructure Planning

Technical issues analysis

2022-08 -Current

Technical Support Engineer

Tenable, Madison, WI

- Managed 20 troubleshooting cases per day
- Performed advanced troubleshooting of Tenable Cloud and Nessus products
- Provided chat and phone support for various Tenable products
- Analyzed provided logs and files
- Configured testing environments to troubleshoot various customer issues
- Monitored vulnerability landscape to better assist customers
- Met with team personnel to share details of discovered issues and recurrent custom complaints
- Provided guidance on installing software to remote clients
- Documented faults and bugs for referral to development staff

2020-06 -2022-08

2020-01 -

2020-06

Systems Engineer

Infratactix, Madison, WI

- Performed various network administration, system administration, and server administration for over 60+ client computing environments
- Utilized various cybersecurity tools such as Nessus and appliances such as Palo Alto to better network security
- Deployed, upgraded, and maintained Windows Server 2008, 2012, 2016 and 2019 operating systems
- Utilized virtualization such as VMWare or Hyper-V and cloud computing technologies like Azure to engineer solutions for clients
- Provided data center infrastructure services and backup for various clients and their environments
- Provided assistance to leadership to better services provided
- Managed Linux systems for web hosting, backup, and email relays
- Documented system configuration, mapping and processes

Systems Administrator

State Of Wisconsin-DCF, Madison, WI

- Automated over 10 weekly tasks utilizing Powershell.
- Managed VMware virtualization pools and environments using VMWare VCenter and VMware VSphere
- Deployed service monitoring solutions to better provide server resources
- Provided escalated end-user support for complex issues
- Managed Exchange and Exchange Online services
- Created Powershell scripts to assist in troubleshooting and automate tasks
- Assisted in design and testing of Microsoft Teams deployment.
- Attended meetings to deliver status reports
- Diagnosed and resolved hardware and software issues

2016-10 -2020-01

Systems Administrator

Infratactix, Madison, WI

- Responsible for monitoring and maintaining over 60 different client networks with approximately 300-500 desktops and laptops
- Resolved and escalated 1000-2000 tickets per month related to connectivity issues
- Walked customers through modem restarts and ISP troubleshooting
- Used Active Directory to manage integrations within network and group policy
- Implemented Linux based online network for end users to remotely access files
- Managed projects such as creating and cleaning up over 10 client networks
- Built entire networks by installing network routers, Cisco switches, firewalls, Windows servers and Hyper-V servers while following HIPAA and PCI compliances
- Installed, configured and maintained Windows Servers 2008 R2, 2012 R2, 2016 and 2017
- Used VMware to manage system domain design and test virtual applications
- Troubleshooted software and hardware issues by using remote desktop services and protocol
- Protected client networks from failures and outside attackers.



Education

2015-07 -2018-08

Bachelor of Science: Information Technology, Network Management

Herzing University, Madison, WI, US - Madison, WI



Accomplishments

- Participated in Hack The Box's Hack the Boo CTF and placed 74th out of over 6000 players.
- Treasurer of DC608, a non-profit Defcon group based out of Madison,WI.
- Trained in Security+, Linux+, and Network+
- Pursuing the OSCP certificate from Offensive Security.



Training Site Profiles

Hack The Box: https://app.hackthebox.com/profile/56933 Blue Team Labs Online: https://blueteamlabs.online/public/user/azuread